AHMED AMINE TALEB BAHMED

Flutter Developer

A highly motivated computer engineer seeking to further my professional career with a technical management position. I have over 2 years of experience in research and development in computational biology, a fast learner (I did not know about biology much), and a passionate about new technologies. Self-motivated, team player with strong organizational and interpersonal skills.



I aim to develop and create interfaces that are intuitive and easy to use at the same time pleasant to the eyes of the users. Contribute to the community.

My long-term goal is to establish a software development company (gather and join a group of developers) in my country, where there is a great need, after having the necessary experience. That's why other than developing my coding and programming skills, I want to develop my leadership and technical management skills as well. Always looking to learn new skills, take on extra responsibilities, and grow professionally.

Eager to join the challenging work environment at your company to utilize my technical skills in creating responsive, user-friendly, and customer-oriented projects.

EXPERIENCE

Antalya, Turkey February 2019 - Present

Antalya, Turkey September 2018 - September 2020

Antalya, Turkey June 2018 - September 2018

Flutter Developer

Freelance

I stared learning flutter by curiosity, until I got few requests to develop applications for the Algerian market, related to food and package delivery, includes geo-localization and tracking, and some analytics features.

Research Assistant

Antalya Bilim University

Research and develop a new algorithm that detects and ranks patient-specific cancer driver genes. Using different techniques I developed an algorithm that finds the best-ranked list of genes that are responsible for cancer of each patient separately, compared to other existing methods.

Front End Developer

Hotech

Hotech provides software solutions for hospitality industry, so I included a scheduler using ExtJs to their web-based system, where you can schedule room reservations for a hotel, and employees' tasks and activities. Furthermore, I developed a room status tracking feature, where the managers track whether a room is clean, empty, or full along with other room's characteristics. Proactively participated in meetings and helped create new practices.

EDUCATION

Antalva, Turkev 2020

M.Sc in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Antalya Bilim University

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email

aminetbo@gmail.com

Address

4300Sok No:32/04 Yesilyurt, Kepez, Antalya, Turkey

Phone

+905511134918

Date of birth

02-17-1994

Nationality

Algerian

Link

https://www.linkedin.com/i n/aminetb2a/

SKILLS

- Flutter
- Java
- Python
- C
- Android
- R
- Machine Learning
- Teamwork
- Flexibility
- Critical Thinking

LANGUAGES

Amazigh (Berber)

Mother Tongue

Arabic

Advanced

French

Advanced

English

Advanced

Turkish

Intermediate

Developed a new method that identifies and ranks a list of cancer driver genes for each patient of a cohort separately. I learned various new concepts and technics of computational biology for two years of research and development, alongside my supervisors and labmates.

Antalya, Turkey 2018

B.Sc in Computer Engineering

Antalya Bilim University

The bachelor's graduation thesis was about detecting car drivers' distractions and taking actions accordingly to regain his/her attention. Using various machine learning technics alongside pre-trained networks, our model could classify each distraction perfectly. We developed an android application that is connected to a raspberry pi (where our model is deployed) by Bluetooth. The application can lock the screen, end a call, or output sounds, and vibrate to prevent the driver from texting, speaking, or sleeping along with other distractions while driving.

PROJECTS

Package Delivery Cross-platform Application 2020

Developed a cross-platform mobile application using Flutter for a startup in Algeria. The goal is to connect e-commerce sellers, or any person in need or delivery to couriers companies, or private drivers. It's like a Uber for just goods and packages.

Brain Tumor Segmentation 2019

The goal was to detect different tumor tissues from normal brain tissues. After reading several papers of previous works, we implemented a U-Net network, but didn't make it to the end, owing to the lack of processing power.

Distraction Driver Detection 2017/2018

It's my bachelor graduation project that detects driver behavior and classifies it using Machine Learning (a challenge published by KAGGLE). The goal is to take an action after detecting the distraction of the driver, using an android application, connected by Bluetooth to a raspberry pi chip that deploys our model. The application can lock the screen, end a call, or emit some noise to prevent the driver from texting, speaking, or sleeping while driving.

Company Calendar 2016

A web-based application that simplifies how groups share plans, schedule events, and communicates statuses.

Finger Spelling Recognition 2016

Using SVM and CNN classifiers we made a model that could translate what a deaf person can tell us by just using a camera.

HTML Editor 2014

A Java program that uses the approach "What you see is what you get", where it runs HTML script and outputs the results in the editor as you work, without the need of a browser.

SOCIAL ACTIVITIES

TED x AIU | Antalya | 2014/2015

Member of the organization team of the known TED organization in Antalya International University for two years in a row.

Tutoring | Calculus 101 | Antalya 2014

Teacher assistant in Calculus 101, in Antalya Bilim University, helping students to understand basics of Mathematics and solve problems.

German

Elementary

Hezarfern for Science and Culture | Istanbul, August 2014

Aerodynamic workshop tutor: teaching the history, fundamentals, and the concepts of aerodynamics, with a plane project at the end of the camp for high school students.

INTERESTS

Sports

American Football player | Corner Back | Antalya 2017/2018 Soccer, Judo, Ping Pong.

Travel and Exploration

Languages | Speaks 5 Languages

I have an interest in the diversity of cultures and traditions. To be able to understand the mentalities learning the languages is mandatory.